Name: Ibi

Email: ibi.olu@gmail.com, Mobile +44 (0) 7985209886.

## **Headline:**

ISEB Certified Test Analyst with over 5years experience in Manual and Automation within Finance and Software Development Environments. Currently an upcoming Software Design Eng. in Test (SDET) and aspiring developer with ability to create an ecommerce websites and webpages.

Deployed an operational project that increased company revenue, currently seeking a position where I can make a valuable contribution to utilise my exceptional skills abilities.

## **Technical Skills:**

Test Tools: Selenium WebDriver, HP ALM, Jenkins, Cucumber, TestNG, Junit.

Bugzilla, and Jira.

Front End: HTML, CSS, UI/UX, JavaScript and XML,

**Web Language:** Python (3.8.1), Java, C#, SQL.

Version Control: GitHub

Framework and libraries: Bootstrap, JQuery, Postman API, Node.js and Json.

**Management**: Agile, Prince2, Scrum and Wireframe.

**Testing Docs**: Test Plan, Test Strategy, UAT, FAT, SAT and defect Reporting.

**Dev TOOLS:** Gitpod, Eclipse, AWS, Google Chrome Dev.

# **Employment History:**

Employer: Freshwater Consulting Duration: Dec2019- May 2020

(A Start-up digital consulting services)

Role: Test Analyst and junior front end developer (Web page improvements)

# Responsibilities:

- Created a Test plan and Test Strategy for the application under test.
- Built manual Test Framework from scratch.
- Used Xpath to inspect HTML AND CSS Elements to validate unique node and manually tested test cases across different operating systems.
- Manipulated the DOM elements in Dev tools to test business functionalities and syntax errors.
- Carried out End To End testing including browser compatibility test of the webpages.
- Improved the design of the landing page by changing the page layout, style and UX design.
- Created goggle maps API's.
- Contributed to the improvement of User Experience of the Webpages.
- Designed and executed UAT test scripts on multiple Devices.
- Testing the web page elements by using Xpath to inspect HTML and CSS elements to validate unique node in DOM.

•

Employer: Hogarth (A digital creativity company)

Duration: Oct 2018-Dec 2019.

Role/Project: QA Test Eng. Intranet Frontend Testing.

Responsibilities:

• Managed the Cucumber test framework in Selenium WebDriver.

- Worked with development team to improve Front End webpages.
- Designed test cases using Jasmine framework to test the JavaScript code.
- Managed defects lifecycle in Jira and
- Tested all links and site navigations of the webpages including cookies.
- Designed and Implemented **Test Plan and Test Strategy** for the test features.
- Developed and executed reusable automation test scripts in Selenium WebDriver.
- Automation and manual WEB API testing, google maps API, maps markers on multiple devices.
- Developed BDD test scenarios to validate full coverage of functional specification.
- Created test cases and regression test suites in Eclipse using TestNG.
- Carried API integration testing to ensure embedded links and external pages displayed.

**Environment**: Agile, Java, Scrum, Eclipse IDE, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, REST API, Jenkins, HTML, CSS, Cucumber, chropath, Agile and Atlassian Jira.

Employer: Simon Schuster (Online Digital)

Role /project: Test Analyst on mobile Apps, Web application and Backend.

Responsibilities:

- Defined test cases for **Front End** web elements to validate Business Requirements.
- Managed task on TRELLO with dev team and business Analyst.
- Manually tested embedded videos, Iframe, Images, buttons and google Maps APIs.
- Tested API End Points Web pages using Postman Rest Client.
- Participated in all scrum ceremonies to ensure the SDLC and Test Strategy are followed.
- Tested the payments gateway links to verify its functionality and other modes.
- Carried out compliance and compatibility test on different devices (IOS AND Android).
- Set up page object model Test frame framework from scratch in Selenium WebDriver.
- Developed regression test cases and coordinated User Acceptance test (UAT).
- Worked with release management to update version control using GIT.
- Managed test environments and produced weekly defects reports and collaborated on Slack.

**Environment:** Scrum, Java, AWS(IDE), DevOPs, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, REST API Testing, Postman, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, XPath, CSS, Safari, IOS, Android, Agile, Trello and GIT.

Employer: PhotoBox Duration: Feb 2016- March 2017
Test Analyst (Functional)

- Worked in agile **environment** along with graphic designer to gather user story, acceptance criteria for each functional requirements and produced test plan and strategy.
- Designed manual test cases based on functional requirements.
- Conducted End to End **UAT** with end users and secured sign off with managements.
- Managed defects and test summary reports in Jira along with developers.
- Used SQL functions to generate and retrieve data for database testing.
- Developed a **UX** process test cases along with User stories for a call to action feature.

- Application testing using Data driven test to allow for multiple data sets for various builds.
- Created basic API tests, Usability, Smoke and sanity testing.
- Worked along with automation team to automate test scripts in Selenium WebDriver.
- Developed automated test scripts and test cases.

**Environment:** HP ALM, Selenium WebDriver, Excel, HTML, CSS, Windows 2010, Microsoft Dynamics, Android, IOS, Agile, Jira and Google Chrome, SDLC.

Employer: Anglian Ruskin Duration: Dec 2013- Dec 2015

**Test Analyst (Manual testing of Front End VLE Website)** 

Carried out end to end testing including Exploratory testing on the VLE website, Responsibilities
are: Writing manual test cases, coordinated and produced UAT scripts, Mapped out sites to identify
URLs, HTML Meta tags, Web services testing, Retesting and regression testing of Bug fixes and
moved to QA Testbeds, run query on SQL databases for number generator, defect reporting .Worked
with release manager to create and maintain build verification (Smoke Testing) and Estimate testing
cycle.

**Environments**: SharePoint 2010, Advanced Excel, .net framework 3.5, Documentum, Citrix server, Ms Silver light and VB.net, WebTrends Enterprise Suite, Webbug for monitoring protocol, Project Server 2010 and SharePoint Server 2010.

Employer: Network Rail Duration: Jan 2007- Sept 2013

**Test Analyst (Information Management)** 

Test analyst on multiple projects encompassing: Implementation pilot, UAT, FAT and SAT

**Project1**: A pension application finance interface system.

**Project2**: Oracle supply chain management Synergy heavy Account payables/Receivables, order management and Inventory: Oracle Supply Chain is an end-to-end supply chain management system that further enables Network Rail to procure and manage material inventory.

**Projects**: Database decommissioning along with Iron Mountain.(Extensive use of SQL) to mirror data base copy.

**Other Projects:** SharePoint Migration, Documentum Software, ERP (Oracle Ebusiness) Implementation Programme, Oracle Hyperion implementation, Testing Oracle Financials payables module and Risk Asset register

**Environments-** Oracle SQL, Bugzilla, SharePoint 2007, QTP, Quality Centre, Load Runner, Moss, XML, ASP.Net Oracle server 2008.

**Achievement:** Successful delivery of all projects and obtained business signed off for all testing cycles and supported 100% completion of migration.

#### **EDUCATION**

Computer Applications in Accounting.

ISEB Intermediate Software Testing.

Front End web development (in progress Code Institute)

Scrum Fundamental Cert/Prince 2 and Agile.

Business Analysis Certificates.

Accounting degree.

Static project (https://daat2.github.io/band-project/)

https://daat2.github.io/ccvitae/